Ramzi Osta

ramziosta.com ramziosta.netlify.app 248-739-1499 ramziosta@gmail.com LinkedIn GitHub

Full Stack Web and App Developer Designer Project Manager

Software engineer with a track record of delivering successful web and mobile apps, increasing visibility and revenue through UX/UI and media integration and improving technology literacy through coaching. Experience in technologies resulted in improved internal processes and data management and increased revenue.

Skills

Programming: React, React-Native, NextJS, Javascript, Java, C#, HTML, CSS, NodeJS, SQL, Unity

Development: NPM, Yarn, REST APIs, Express, Javalin, Maven, Apollo, GraphQL, Stripe

Database and CMS: MongoDB, Postgres, Firebase, Strapi, Sanity

DevOps: Netlify, Docker, Heroku, Github, AWS

Languages: English, Arabic, Spanish

Experience

Freelance, Software Engineer, Web Developer

2020-Current

- Build web and mobile apps, set up servers, and databases using SEO techniques to create successful
 advertising campaigns and increased job offers.
- Created visually appealing websites, applied UX/UI techniques and various media, including music and video production increasing business visibility, revenue and online ratings.
- Coach diverse groups through personalized instruction, workshops, and materials to improve technology literacy and proficiency.

Revature 2022-2022

Ticketing System

Horescope

Developed an employee app utilizing Java, Javalin, Maven, Postgres, Redis, and Docker for user registration, login, permissions, ticket submission, and approval and improved internal processes.

- Built a Horoscope Web App using APIs and queries to retrieve user-specific data and manipulate the

 DOM
- Implemented a backend server using Java, Javalin, and Maven, and integrated it with a Postgres
 database and Redis for data storage and retrieval using Docker that resulted in improved data
 management and scalability.
- Technologies: Java, Javalin, Maven, HTML, CSS, Postgres, SQL

Projects

PROGRAMMING

Full Stack Banking Application Live site github

- Developed and built a full stack app with user registration and sign-in, and implemented full CRUD functionality with integration to backend servers and persistent data storage.
- Utilized key concepts such as authorization and authentication with JWT and session cookies, and managed routing with effective testing of APIs using Postman and Swagger
- Technologies: React, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, SASS, NodeJS, MongoDB, Express, JWT

Ramzi Osta Portfolio Website and App App Website

- Utilized EmailJS, Calendly, and Sanity CMS as a flexible and scalable backend solution, allowing for dynamic content management and seamless integration with the app, resulting in a dynamic and growing user experience.
- Technologies: React, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, SASS, Framer Motion, Sanity, Netlify, mailJS, Calendly

Media and Publication App App

- Utilized Firebase to build a scalable and efficient web application, utilizing features such as real-time data storage, user authentication, and serverless computing.
- Technologies: React, Javascript, Firebase, Github

DESIGN AND UI/UX

Mobile App Clickable Mockup

Mockup

Created interactive and realistic mobile device clickable mockups, allowing stakeholders and team

members to experience and test the user interface and user flow before development

Technologies: Adobe Illustrator, Indesign, Photoshop, XD, Figma, Balsamiq.

Branding Guide

Brand Guide 1 Brand Guide 2

• Developed and implemented comprehensive branding guidelines, ensuring consistency and cohesiveness across all mediums and platforms, resulting in a strong and recognizable brand identity.

User Case Study and Wireframe

Case Study

• Utilized wireframe design techniques to effectively plan and test the functionality and usability of the website or application, resulting in a user-centered and efficient final product.

Education

Massachusetts Institute of Technology xPro Full Stack Web Development with MERN

August 2021- May 2022

University of Michigan

Web Development January 2021 - Mar 2021

University of Michigan

SQL Query Language May 2021 - June 2021

Cal Arts, California

Graphic Design, UX UI August 2020 - December 2020

Codecademy

Mobile Development in React Native
C# Programming Language
Java Programming Language

December 2022- January 2023 August 2022- September 2022 July 2022 - August 2022